A Finding Aid to the Diógenes Ballester papers, 1973-2020, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Professional Activity Files, 1973-2018; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 2-5
  - San Juan Biennial, Archival Resource Key
    - Notes for Draft Exhibition Catalog, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - "Perspectives: On the XII San Juan Biennial of Latin American and Caribbean Printmaking At the Transition to the 21st Century" by Diogenes Ballester, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Reflection on Status of Printmaking at San Juan Bienal 1998, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Symposium Lectures, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - XII Bienal de San Juan, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 58-59)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 60-61)
  - Miscellaneous, 1996-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
- Printed Material, 1975-2020; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  Printed material consists of articles on and written by Ballester, clippings, newsletters, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, press releases, and posters.
  - "6 Bienal Internacional de Arte Valparaiso, Chile" Catalog, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Articles, circa 1990-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
  - Articles, Cuba and Grenada, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Articles on the Phoenix, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Centro Journal, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1979-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13-17)
  - "Creacion Arte y Letras", 1975-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - College Art Association Newsletters, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Dimensions of the Americas: Art and Social Change in Latin America and the United States" by Shifra M. Goldman, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "El Dia Que me Disfrace de Vejigante", 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Espiritus Rumberos" by Natalia Bolivar and Jose L. Diaz de Villegas, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1982-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23-28)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1982-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29-33)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Other Artists, 1982-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
  - Guerra Manual of Paints and Pigments, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - "The Institute for Latino Studies at the University of Notre Dame", circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Institute of Puerto Rico 50th Annual Cultural Awards Program, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Newsletters, 1982-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - "New York: A Fantasy as Seen Through the Eyes of Class 4-210B", 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Reproductions From "Reproduce & Revolt" Book, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Posters, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Report to the Governor of Puerto Rico, The Honorable Pedro Rossello, Special Commission on Vieques, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - David Alfaro Siqueiros Article, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Por Los Senderos del Sur" by J. A. Carrero, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1991-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
  - "Voices From Our Communities" Exhibition Catalog, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983-2020; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8-14)
- Photographic Material, circa 1990-2011; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 6
  Photographic material consists of photographs of Ballester, photographs of Ballester with friends and family, photographs of an exhibition, and photographs and slides of artwork.
  - Photographs, Ballester, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, Ballester with Family and Friends, circa 2000-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Photographs, Personal, circa 1990-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, "Ancestral Confessions: Historical Evidence of a City" Exhibition, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, Exhibition, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, Artwork, circa 2008-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20-24)
  - Slides, Artwork, circa 1998-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Reproductions/Photocopies, Miscellaneous Photographs, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)